Kedgard Cordero

Software Engineer

Email: geckob4i@gmail.com

Phone: 651-231-0126

Location: Lino Lakes, Minnesota

GitHub: https://github.com/Kenny4297

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kedgard-cordero/
Portfolio: https://kenny4297.github.io/React-Portfolio/

About Me

2 years of self-study with a certificate from the University of Minnesota Coding Boot Camp. Enjoys working in fast paced environments and learning anything regarding software development. Curious with a love to solve problems, always malleable to company standards.

Skills

Front-End: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery

Back-end: Python, Node.js, Express.js

Databases: SQL, MongoDB

Additional Tools: TensorFlow.js, Sequelize, MySQL, Mongoose, Jest

Experience

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp, University of Minnesota

Minneapolis, Minnesota

2022-2023

- Lead Programmer for group project 1 and 3, Project Manager for group project 2.
- Average assignment result of 101.58% with consistent feedback regarding clean, polished code.
- Directed weekly tutor sessions for fellow students.
- Improved professor's MERN Authentication stack starter code.

Hazelwood Food and Drink, Tonka Bay - Server Trainer

Tonka Bay, Minnesota

2016-2022

- Lead trainer for over 140 servers at Tonka Bay location in collaboration with corporate management.
- Onboarded over 90 servers while opening 3 different multi-million-dollar restaurants across Minneapolis-St. Paul.
- Refined and revised training materials for multiple departments including Spanish translation services.

Featured Projects

<u>Paw Prints</u> | A full-stack web app that allows users to post lost pets and use machine learning image recognition to identify any breed of lost animal.

- Responsibilities: Image Recognition (TensorFlow.js/MobileNet), Image uploading (Cloudinary)
- Technologies: React, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, bcrypt, Mongoose, Twillo, TensorFlow.js/MobileNet
- Deployed at: https://pet-finder-application.herokuapp.com/

Weather App | A front end application that tracks the weather and the five-day forecast in any city around the globe.

- Responsibilities: Sole Developer
- Technologies: JavaScript, Bootstrap, Open Weather API
- Deployed at: https://kenny4297.github.io/Weather-App-API/

Education

Mankato State University, Mankato

Teaching and Learning (MS)

2014-2016

- Documented 800 hours as student teacher
 - Owatonna High School, Minnesota
 - Waseca High School, Minnesota
 - Liceo Experimental Bilingue, Turrialba, Costa Rica